<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Kuan Zhou</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistivity calculation of tetralayer graphene</title>
      <link>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/tetralayer-graphene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/tetralayer-graphene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 2017-Current&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authors: Kuan Zhou, Yanmeng Shi, Supeng Ge, Jeanie Lau, Roger K. Lake&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory and modeling work in this project supports the experimental work of Prof. Jeanie Lau’s group. I am tasked with providing electronic band structures, Landau level energies, and resistivity for tetralayer graphene using the electronic structure calculated from a tight-binding model as input into the Boltzmann transport equation within a relaxation time approximation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlayer resistivity of misoriented MoS$_2$</title>
      <link>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/interlayer-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/interlayer-resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dec. 2014-Feb. 2017&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authors: Kuan Zhou, Darshana Wickramaratne, Supeng Ge, Shanshan Su, Amrit De, Roger K. Lake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The electron and hole interlayer resistance of misoriented bilayer MoS$_2$ were determined as a function of the misorientation angle. The approach employed electronic structure calculations using the Vienna Ab initio simulation package (&lt;a href=&#34;http://cms.mpi.univie.ac.at/vasp/vasp/vasp.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VASP&lt;/a&gt;) combined with NEGF calculations of the interlayer resistivity. I found that the electron and hole resistivities differed by several orders of magnitude depending on the rotation angle, and how this property could be exploited in the design of a high-frequency bipolar junction transistor or heterostructure bipolar transistor. This work has been published in Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics as an &lt;a href=&#34;http://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlepdf/2017/cp/c6cp08927e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Advanced article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking for material simulation package-OpenMX</title>
      <link>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/benchmarking-openmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/benchmarking-openmx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aug. 2015-Oct. 2015&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authors: Kuan Zhou, Roger K. Lake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmx-square.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenMX&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source software package for nano-scale material simulations based on density functional theories (DFT), norm-conserving pseudopotentials, and pseudo-atomic localized basis functions. Systems consisting of 1000 atoms can be treated using the conventional diagonalization method. Non-quilibrium Green functions (NEGF) is also implemented into the package. To help calculate electron transport for several systems with large computing requirements, I benchmarked the performance of this software.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of GRAPE algorithm in quantum control techniques</title>
      <link>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/optimization-grape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kzhou003.github.io/project/optimization-grape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;June 2012-June 2013&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authors: Kuan Zhou, Nanyang Xu, Xinhua Peng&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed quantum control techniques in NMR systems, including optimization of the Gradient Ascent Pulse Engineering algorithm (GRAPE), and completed the task of algorithm development and pulse calculations in 5-bit systems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
